So you may have noticed when my player character moves towards the right, they're facing the correct
direction.
However, if my player character moves towards the left, they're not facing the correct direction and
it looks kind of weird.
So let's fix that now.
If I head over to my player, BP.
We'll go to our input access move, right.
And we can just delete this print shrink.
The first thing I want to do is create a new variable.
So we just go to create a new variable and call this move.
Right.
Question mark.
And does compiler.
I'm just going to draw and dispute right elbow and look for set move.
Right.
So this is the booty.
Invariable booty and variables can be either true or false.
And we're basically going to use this variable to help us determine whether our characters should be
moving towards the right or left.
So what we're going to do is just drag off this x value and check to see if it is greater than zero.
If this is greater than zero, we'll just try and look for Branch.
If that is true, then when I say I knew right to be true.
So you can just hook up all these nets.
However, if our access value is not greater than zero, then we are going to do another check.
So we'll drag off the study and check to see if this is less than zero.
So the truck filled up for brunch.
And look up folks into here.
So if our actual value is less than zero and that is true, then we're dragging our move, Right?
And just set it to it's untrue.
And we'll just hook up folks into here.
So what we've done is if our access value is ever greater than XR, we will set this variable called
move right to be true.
However, if a value is ever less than zero, then we'll set this variable to be false.
Next, we're going to go up and look for event tick.
So the way Event Tick works is every single frame is going to run this node and on event tick, we're
going to make sure that our character is always facing the correct direction.
So over that tick, we first want to drag in our character ribbon, and off here we'll look for velocity.
I'm going to get the velocity of our character.
We just want to right click on this value and click split up.
We're only going to be concerned with the velocity of our character and the x axis, because as I mentioned
earlier in our two D game, our character is only going to be moving in the x axis and we're going to
do is going to drag up here and look for compare flipped.
Now we're going to compare the velocity of our cut and the x axis with the values error.
If our character's velocity in the axis is ever greater than zero, that means our player character
should be facing towards the right.
So in order to make that happen, what we can do is just right click and forget control.
Let's all get the controller that we're controlling.
The player character, as I'm going to do, is just drag a player out for is valid.
This will just make sure that we have a valid reference to our controller.
And if that is valid, then we're going to set the rotation of our player character to be facing towards
the right.
We can do that by dragging off this node and looking for set control rotation.
Then under this new rotation value, we can strike up here.
And for me, the rotator.
And we can write the values that we want our character to have and be X, Y, and Z.
If I head over to the viewport and just like my Sprite, currently we can see my sprite rotation in
the X, Y and Z is there for my character.
It's facing the right.
So here am I, Bancroft.
I'm just going to leave this value at 000.
If my player character is mostly in the x axis is ever less than zero, that means my player character
is moving towards the left.
We want our characters to be facing the left.
So copy all these nodes.
Press control C and then control V.
And from this node, the last man to hear.
If I go back to my people and just like my spirit in the Z, if I make this value 180, my spirit will
flip and they'll be facing towards the left.
I'm just going to put this back at zero.
And head over to my bank.
So when my characters velocity in the x axis is less than zero, we'll make it so my character is facing
towards the left.
So here under Z, we want to put a value of 180.
And if I play characters velocity, the x axis is equal to zero.
Then what we're going to do is drag in this big right variable, which will be determined by here.
And to strike a fair and full branch.
If the mood right variable is true and we'll make it so I'll play a character.
It's facing towards the right.
And if our move right variable is false, we'll make it so our player character is facing towards the
left.
And we'll just go from here to here.
And just go compile and save.
So if I just close this and go play.
If I read this right, I captivates all the right and left.
Whoops.
So that's not working.
If we head back to our player character.
We just want to set our spring goal.
And currently its rotation is set to rotate.
We need to change it so that it's set to the world.
Go compile.
Save.
Close this.
And now we go play.
When I pressed the right mouse button.
Sorry.
When I press the right keyboard.
My capital mutual's the right.
If I press the left key bar, my character will move towards the left.
Now, normally in 2D platformer games, a character starts facing the right by default.
So under my play beep, just make sure the right variable is checked so our character will start the
game facing towards the right.
So if I go play, my character starts facing towards the right and I can move around and just the next
thing I'm going to do is use the paper Z animation system to make it so our character will play some
different animations and then that jumping and moving.